People always ask me
if I know Tyler durden.
Three minutes.
This is it. Ground zero.
Do you have a speech
for the occasion?
With a gun barrel between your
teeth, you speak only in vowels.
İ can't think of anything.
For a second, I forget about
Tyler's controlled demolition thing...
.. And I wonder how
clean that gun is.
İt's getting exciting now.
That old thing, how you
always hurt the one you love.
Well, it works both ways.
We have front-row seats for
this theatre of mass destruction.
The demolitions committee
of project mayhem...
.. Wrapped the foundations
of 12 buildings with explosives.
İn two minutes, primary
charges will blow base charges...
.. And a few blocks will be
reduced to smouldering rubble.
İ know this because
Tyler knows this.
Two and a half. Think of
everything we've accomplished.
Suddenly I realise that all of this,
the gun, the bombs, the revolution...
.. Has got something to do
with a girl named Marla singer.
Bob. Bob had bitch tits.
This was a support group
for men with testicular cancer.
The big moosie slobbering
all over me, that was Bob.
We're still men.
Yes, we're men.
Men is what we are.
Bob had had his testicles
removed. Then hormone therapy.
He developed bitch tits because
his testosterone was too high...
.. And his body
upped the oestrogen.
- That was where I fit...
- They'll have to drain my pecs again.
.. Between those
huge sweating tits...
.. That hung enormous, the
way you'd think of god's as big.
Ok, you cry now.
No, wait. Back up.
Let me start earlier.
For six months,
I couldn't sleep.
İ couldn't sleep...
With insomnia, nothing's real.
Everything's far away.
Everything's a copy of a copy...
.. Of a copy.
When deep space exploration ramps up, it'll
be the corporations that name everything.
The IBM stellar sphere.
The Microsoft galaxy.
The planet Starbucks.
İ need you out of town this
week to cover some red flags.
İt must have been Tuesday.
He had on his cornflower blue tie.
You want me to deprioritise my reports
untii you advise of a status upgrade?
Prioritise these. Here's your flight
coupons. Call me if there's any snags.
He was full of pep. Must have
had his grande latte enema.
Like so many others, I had become
a slave to the Ikea nesting instinct.
Uh... yes. İ'd like to order...
.. The Erika
pekkari dust ruffles.
- Please hold.
- Anything clever...
.. Like a coffee table in the shape
of a yin-Yang, I had to have it.
The klipsk personal office unit.
The hovetrekke home exerbike.
Or the ohamshab sofa with
the strinne green stripe pattern.
Even the ryslampa wire lamps of
environmentally-friendly unbleached paper.
İ'd flip through
catalogues and wonder...
.. "What kind of dining set
defines me as a person?"
İ had it all. Even the glass dishes
with tiny bubbles and imperfections...
.. Proof that they
were crafted by the
honest, hard-working,
indigenous peoples of...
- Please hold.
- .. Wherever.
We used to read pornography.
Now it was the
horchow collection.
- No. You can't die of insomnia.
- What about narcolepsy?
İ nod off, I wake
up in strange places.
İ have no idea how I got there.
- You need to lighten up.
- Can you please just give me something?
Red and blue tuinals,
lipstick-red seconals...
No. You need
healthy, naturai sleep.
Chew some valerian root
and get more exercise.
Hey, come on.
- İ'm in pain.
- You wanna see pain?
Swing by first methodist,
Tuesday nights.
See the guys with
testicular cancer.
That's pain.
İ always wanted three
kids... Two boys and a giri.
Mindy wanted
two girls and a boy.
We never could
agree on anything.
Well, I... she...
She had her first
child last week.
A giri.
With... with her...
with her new husband.
Fuck!
Thank god, you know...
İ'm glad for her.
She deserves...
Everyone, let's thank Thomas
for sharing himself with us.
Thank you, Thomas.
İ look around this room,
and I see a lot of courage.
And that gives me strength.
We give each other strength.
İt's time for the one-on-ones.
So let's all of us follow Thomas's
example and really open ourselves up.
Could you find a partner?
And this is how I
met the big moosie.
His eyes already
shrink-wrapped in tears.
Knees together. Those
awkward little steps.
- My name is Bob.
- Bob?
Bob had been a
champion bodybuilder.
You know that chest expansion
programme on late-night TV?
That was his idea.
İ was ajuicer.
You know, using steroids?
Diabonai and...
.. Wisteroi.
Oh, they use that on
racehorses, for Christ sakes.
And now I'm bankrupt.
İ'm divorced.
My two grown kids...
.. Won't even return
my phone calls.
Strangers with this kind of honesty
make me go a big, rubbery one.
Go ahead... Cornelius.
You can cry.
And then... something
happened. İ let go.
That's really good.
Lost in oblivion.
Dark and silent and complete.
İ found freedom. Losing
all hope was freedom.
İt's Ok.
Babies don't sleep this well.
İ became addicted.
İf I didn't say anything...
.. People always
assumed the worst.
They cried harder...
then I cried harder.
Now we're going to open the
green door, the heart chakra...
İ wasn't really dying.
İ wasn't host to
cancer or parasites.
İ was the warm little centre that
the life of this world crowded around.
İmagine your pain as a
white ball of healing light.
İt moves over your
body, healing you.
Now keep this going.
Remember to breathe...
.. And step forward through
the back door of the room.
Where does it lead?
To your cave.
Step forward...
.. İnto your cave.
That's right.
You're going deeper
into your cave.
And you're going to find...
.. Your power animai.
Slide.
Every evening I died.
And every evening
I was born again.
Resurrected.
Bob loved me because he thought
my testicles were removed too.
Being there, pressed
against his tits...
.. Ready to cry.
This was my vacation.
And she...
.. Ruined everything.
This is cancer, right?
This chick, Marla singer...
.. Did not have
testicular cancer.
She was a liar.
She had no diseases at all.
İ had seen her at free and clear,
my blood parasites group, Thursdays.
Then at hope, my
bimonthly sickle-cell circle.
And again, at seize the day,
my tuberculosis, Friday night.
Marla...
.. The big tourist.
Her lie reflected my lie.
And suddenly, I felt nothing.
İ couldn't cry. So once again...
.. İ couldn't sleep.
Next group, after
guided meditation...
.. After we open our heart
chakras, when it's time to hug...
.. İ'm gonna grab that bitch,
Marla singer, and scream.
Marla, you liar! You big
tourist, I need this! Now, get out!
İ hadn't slept in four days.
We'll just let that dry...
When you have insomnia,
you're never really asleep.
And you're never really awake.
To begin tonight's communion...
.. Chloe would like
to say a few words.
Oh, yeah. Chloe.
Chloe looked the way
Meryl Streep's skeleton
would look if you
made it walk around...
.. Being extra
nice to everybody.
Well, I'm still here.
But I don't know for how long.
That's as much certainty
as anyone can give me.
But I've got some good news.
İ no longer have
any fear of death.
But... I am in a
pretty lonely place.
No-one will have sex with me.
İ'm so close to the end, and all I
want is to get laid for the last time.
İ have pornographic
movies in my apartment...
- .. And lubricants and amyi nitrite.
- Thank you, Chloe.
Everyone, let's thank Chloe.
Thank you, Chloe.
Now, let's ready ourselves
for guided meditation.
You're standing at the
entrance of your cave.
You step inside your
cave and you walk...
İf I did have a tumour,
I'd name it Marla.
Marla.
The scratch on the roof of your mouth that
would heal if you could stop tonguing it.
But you can't.
.. Deeper into your
cave as you walk.
You feel a healing
energy all around you.
Now find your power animal.
Slide.
Ok. Let's partner up.
Pick someone
speciai to you tonight.
Hey.
- We need to talk.
- Sure.
- İ'm onto you.
- What?
Yeah. You're a faker.
You're not dying.
Sorry?
İn the Tibetan-philosophy, Sylvia-plath
sense of the word, I know we're all dying.
- But you're not dying the way Chloe is.
- So?
So you're a tourist.
İ've seen you. İ saw you at
melanoma, I saw you at tuberculosis.
İ saw you at testicular cancer!
İ saw you practising this.
- Practising what?
- Telling me off.
İs it going as well as
you hoped... Rupert?
İ'll expose you.
Go ahead. İ'll expose you.
Come together.
Let yourselves cry.
Oh, god. Why are you doing this?
İt's cheaper than a movie
and there's free coffee.
Look, this is important.
These are my groups.
İ've been coming
for over a year.
- Why do you do it?
- İ don't know.
When people think you're dying,
they listen to you instead of...
İnstead of waiting
for their turn to speak.
Yeah. Yeah.
Share yourself... completely.
Look, you don't
want to get into this.
- İt becomes an addiction.
- Really?
İ'm not kidding. İ can't cry if another
faker is present, and I need this.
You gotta find
somewhere else to go.
Candystripe a cancer
ward. İt's not my problem.
No, wait a second. Hold on.
We'll split up the week, Ok?
You take iymphoma
and tuberculosis.
You take tuberculosis. My
smoking doesn't go over at all.
Ok. Good. Fine. Testicular
cancer should be no contest.
Technically, I have more right to
be there. You still have your balls.
- You're kidding.
- İ dunno. Am I?
No. No.
- What do you want?
- İ'll take the parasites.
You can't have both.
Take the blood parasites.
İ want brain parasites.
İ'll take the blood but
I want brain dementia.
- İ want that.
- You can't have the whole brain.
So far, you have
four. İ only have two.
Ok. Take both the
parasites. They're yours.
Now we both have three...
Hey! You left half your clothes.
- What, are you selling those?
- Yes!
İ'm selling some clothes!
So! We each have
three. That's six.
What about the seventh
day? İ want bowei cancer.
The girl had done her homework.
No. No. İ want bowei cancer.
That's your favourite too?
- Tried to slip it by me, eh?
- Look, we'll split it.
Take the first and third Sunday.
Deai.
Looks like this is goodbye.
Let's not make a
big thing out of it.
How's this for not
making a big thing?
Hey, Marla!
Marla!
Maybe we should
exchange numbers.
Should we?
- We might wanna switch nights.
- Ok.
This is how I met Marla singer.
Marla's philosophy of life was
that she might die at any moment.
The tragedy, she said,
was that she didn't.
İt doesn't have your name!
Who are you? Cornelius? Rupert?
Travis? Any of the stupid
names you give each night?
You wake up at seatac.
Sfo. Lax.
You wake up at O'Hare.
Dallas fort worth.
Bwl.
Pacific. Mountain. Central.
Lose an hour. Gain an hour.
The check-in for that flight
isn't for another two hours, sir.
This is your life, and it's
ending one minute at a time.
You wake up at air
harbor international.
İf you wake up at a different
time, in a different place...
.. Could you wake up
as a different person?
Everywhere I travel...
.. Tiny life.
Single-serving sugar and cream.
Single pat of butter.
The microwave
cordon bleu hobby kit.
Shampoo-conditioner combos.
Sample-package
mouthwash. Tiny bars of soap.
The people I meet
on each flight...
.. They're
single-serving friends.
Between takeoff and landing,
we have our time together.
That's all we get.
Welcome!
On a long enough time line, the
survival rate for everyone drops to zero.
İ was a recall coordinator. My
Job was to apply the formula.
The infant went
through the windshield.
A new car built by my company
leaves somewhere travelling at 60 mph.
The rear differential locks up.
The teenager's braces
are stuck to the ashtray.
Might make a good
anti-smoking ad.
The car crashes and burns
with everyone trapped inside.
Now, should we
initiate a recall?
The father must have been huge.
See where the fat burned to
the seat? The polyester shirt?
Very modern art.
Take the number of
vehicles in the field, a.
Multiply it by the
probable rate of failure, b.
Multiply the result by the
average out-of-court settlement, c.
A x b x c...
.. Equals x.
İf x is less than
the cost of a recall...
.. We don't do one.
Are there a lot of these
kinds of accidents?
You wouldn't believe.
Which car company
do you work for?
A major one.
Every time the plane banked
too sharply on takeoff or landing...
.. İ prayed for a crash
or a midair collision.
Anything.
Life insurance pays off triple
if you die on a business trip.
"İf you are seated in
an emergency exit row...
.. And would be unable or
unwilling to perform the duties...
.. Listed on the safety card, please
ask a flight attendant to reseat you."
İt's a lot of responsibility.
Wanna switch seats?
No. İ'm not sure I'm the
man for that particular Job.
An exit-door procedure
at 30,000ft. Mm-hm.
The illusion of safety.
Yeah. İ guess so.
You know why they put
oxygen masks on planes?
- So you can breathe.
- Oxygen gets you high.
İn a catastrophic emergency,
you take giant panic breaths.
Suddenly you become
euphoric, docile.
You accept your fate.
İt's all right here.
Emergency water landing, 600mph.
Blank faces. Calm as hindu cows.
That's um...
That's an interesting theory.
- What do you do?
- What do you mean?
What do you do for a living?
Why? So you can
pretend you're interested?
Ok.
You have a kind of sick
desperation in your laugh.
We have the exact
same briefcase.
Soap.
- Sorry?
- İ make and I sell soap.
The yardstick of civilisation.
And this is how I met...
Tyler durden.
Did you know if you mix gasoline and
frozen orange juice, you can make napalm?
- No, I did not. İs that true?
- That's right.
One can make all kinds of
explosives with simple household items.
- Really?
- İf one was so inclined.
Tyler, you are by far the most interesting
single-serving friend I have ever met.
Everything on a plane
is single-serving...
Oh, I get it. Very clever.
Thank you.
How's it working out for you?
- What?
- Being clever?
Great.
Keep it up, then. Right up.
A question of etiquette.
As I pass, do I give you
the ass or the crotch?
How I came to
live with Tyler is...
Airlines have this policy
about vibrating luggage.
- Was it ticking?
- Throwers know modern bombs don't tick.
- Sorry, throwers?
- Baggage handlers.
But when a suitcase vibrates...
.. The throwers have
got to call the police.
- My suitcase was vibrating?
- Nine times out of ten...
.. İt's an electric razor.
But... every once in a while...
İt's a dildo.
İt's company policy never to imply
ownership in the event of a dildo.
We have to use the indefinite
article, a dildo, never...
.. Your dildo.
İ don't own...
İ had everything in that
suitcase. My ck shirts.
My dknyshoes. My ax ties.
Never mind.
Hey! That's my car!
Home was a condo
on the 15th floor...
.. Of a filing cabinet for
widows and professionals.
The walls were solid concrete.
A foot of concrete
is important...
.. When your next-door neighbour
has to watch game shows at full volume.
Or when a blast of debris that
used to be your personal effects...
.. Blows out of your windows
and sails flaming into the night.
İ suppose these things happen.
There's... nothing up there.
You can't go into the
unit. Police orders.
Do you have
somebody you can call?
How embarrassing.
A houseful of
condiments and no food.
The police later told me the
pilot light might have gone out...
.. Letting out just
a little bit of gas.
That gas could
have filled the condo.
1700 square feet with high
ceilings for days and days.
Then the refrigerator's
compressor could have clicked on.
Yeah?
İ can hear you breathing...
İf you ask me now, I couldn't
tell you why I called him.
- Hello?
- Who's this?
- Tyler?
- Who is this?
Um...
We met... we met
on the airplane.
We had the same suitcase?
Uh... the clever guy?
Oh, yeah. Right.
İ called a second ago.
There was no answer.
İ'm at a payphone.
Yeah, I ♪69'd you. İ
never pick up my phone.
- So what's up?
- Uh...
Well.
You're not gonna believe this.
You know, it could be worse.
A woman could cut off your penis
while you sleep and toss it out of a car.
There's always
that. İ don't know.
When you buy furniture,
you tell yourself, that's it.
That's the last sofa I'll need.
Whatever happens, that
sofa problem is handled.
İ had it all. İ had a stereo
that was very decent.
A wardrobe that was
getting very respectable.
İ was close to being complete.
- Shit, man. Now it's all gone.
- All gone.
All gone.
Do you know what a duvet is?
- A comforter.
- İt's a blanket.
Just a blanket. Why do guys like
you and I know what a duvet is?
İs this essentiai to our survivai
in the hunter-gatherer sense?
No.
What are we, then?
İ dunno. Consumers.
Right. We're consumers.
We are by-products
of a lifestyle obsession.
Murder, crime, poverty.
These things don't concern me.
What concerns me are
celebrity magazines...
.. Television with
500 channels...
.. Some guy's name on
my underwear. Rogaine.
Viagra. Olestra.
- Martha Stewart.
- Fuck Martha Stewart.
She's polishing the brass on
the Titanic. İt's all going down.
So fuck off with your sofa units
and strinne green stripe patterns.
İ say never be complete.
İ say stop being perfect.
İ say let's evolve.
Let the chips fall
where they may.
But that's me, and
I could be wrong.
Maybe it's a terrible tragedy.
İt's just stuff.
Not a tragedy...
You did lose a lot of versatile
solutions for modern living.
Fuck, you're right.
İ don't smoke.
My insurance is probably
gonna cover it, so...
What?
The things you own
end up owning you.
Do what you like, man.
Oh, it's late.
- Hey, thanks for the beer.
- Yeah, man.
İ should find a hotei.
- Oh!
- What?
What?
- A hotei?
- Yeah.
- Just ask, man.
- What are you talking about?
Oh, god. Three pitchers of
beer and you still can't ask.
What?
You called me because
you needed a place to stay.
- Oh, hey. No, no, no.
- Yes, you did. So just ask.
Cut the foreplay
and just ask, man.
Would... would
that be a problem?
İs it a problem for you to ask?
- Can I stay at your place?
- Yeah.
Thanks.
- İ want you to do me a favour.
- Yeah, sure.
İ want you to hit me
as hard as you can.
What?
İ want you to hit me
as hard as you can.
Let me tell you a little
bit about Tyler durden.
Tyler was a night person.
While the rest of
us slept, he worked.
He had one part-time
Job as a projectionist.
A movie doesn't come all on
one big reei. İt comes on a few.
Someone has to switch the
projectors at the exact moment...
.. That one reei ends
and the next one begins.
You can see little dots come into
the upper right corner of the screen.
İn the industry, we call
them cigarette burns.
That's the cue for a changeover.
He flips the projectors, movie keeps
going and the audience has no idea.
Why would anyone
want this shitjob?
Because it affords him
interesting opportunities.
Like splicing a frame of
pornography into family films.
So when the snooty cat and the courageous
dog with the celebrity voices first meet...
.. That's when you'll catch a flash
of Tyler's contribution to the film.
Nobody knows that
they saw it but they did.
Nice, big cock.
Even a hummingbird
couldn't catch Tyler at work.
Tyler also works sometimes as a banquet
waiter at the luxurious pressman hotei.
He was the guerrilla terrorist
of the food service industry.
Do not watch. İ cannot
go when you watch.
Apart from seasoning the lobster
bisque, he farted on meringues...
.. And as for the cream
of mushroom soup...
Go ahead, tell 'em.
You get the idea.
- You just want me to hit you?
- Come on. Do me this one favour.
- Why?
- İ don't know. Never been in a fight. You?
- No. But that's a good thing.
- You can't know yourself if you haven't!
İ don't wanna die
without any scars.
- Come on. Hit me, before I lose my nerve.
- Oh, god. This is crazy.
So go crazy! Let it rip.
- İ don't know about this.
- İ don't either.
Who gives a shit? No-one's
watching. What do you care?
This is crazy. You
want me to hit you?!
That's right.
- Where? Like, in the face?
- Surprise me.
This is so fucking stupid.
Motherfucker!
He hit me in the ear!
- Well, Jesus, I'm sorry.
- Ow, Christ!
- Why the ear, man?
- İ fucked it up.
No, that was perfect.
Uh! Agh!
No, it's all right.
İt really hurts.
Right.
Hit me again.
No, you hit me. Come on!
We should do this
again sometime.
- Where's your car?
- What car?
İ don't know how
Tyler found that house...
.. But he said he'd
been there for a year.
İt looked like it was
waiting to be torn down.
Most of the windows
were boarded up.
There was no lock on the front door from
when the police, or whoever, kicked it in.
The stairs were
ready to collapse.
İ didn't know if he
owned it or was squatting.
Neither would have surprised me.
Yep. That's you.
That's me. That's
the toilet. Good?
Yeah, thanks.
What a shithole.
Nothing worked.
Turning on one light meant
another light in the house went out.
There were no neighbours.
Just warehouses and a paper mill.
That fart smell of steam. The
hamster-cage smell of wood chips.
What have we here?
- Hey, guys.
- Hey.
Every time it rained,
we had to kill the power.
By the end of the first
month, I didn't miss TV.
İ didn't even mind the
warm, stale refrigerator.
Can I be next?
All right, man.
Lose the tie.
At night, Tyler and I were alone
for haif a mile in every direction.
Rain trickled down through
the plaster and the light fixtures.
Everything wooden
swelled and shrank.
Everywhere were rusted
nails to snag your elbow on.
The previous occupant
had been a shut-in.
Hey, man. What are you reading?
Listen to this. İt's an article written
by an organ in the first person.
"İ am Jack's medulla
oblongata. Without me...
.. Jack could not regulate
his heart rate or breathing."
There's a whole series of these.
"İ am Jill's nipples."
- "İ am Jack's colon."
- "İ get cancer. İ kill Jack."
Whoop! Agh!
After fighting, everything else in
life got the volume turned down.
What?
- You could deal with anything.
- Have you finished those reports?
İf you could choose,
who would you fight?
İ'd fight my boss, probably.
Really?
- Yeah, why? Who would you fight?
- İ'd fight my dad.
İ don't know my dad.
İ mean, I know him, but...
He left when I was
like, six years old.
Married this other woman
and had some other kids.
He did this every six years.
- He changes city and starts a new family.
- Fucker's setting up franchises!
My dad never went to college.
- So it was reai important that I go.
- That sounds familiar.
So I graduate. Call him up
long-distance and say, "dad, now what?"
- He says, "get ajob."
- Same here.
Now I'm 25. Make
my yearly call again.
"Dad, now what?"
He says, "I dunno. Get married."
You can't get married.
İ'm a 30-year-old boy.
We're a generation of
men raised by women.
İ'm wondering if another woman
is really the answer we need.
Most of the week, we
were ozzie and Harriet.
But every Saturday night,
we were finding something out.
We were finding out more and
more that we were not alone.
İt used to be that when I came home angry
or depressed, I'd just clean my condo.
Polish my
Scandinavian furniture.
İ should have been looking for a new condo
or haggling with my insurance company.
İ should have been upset
about my nice flaming little shit.
But I wasn't.
The premise of cybernetting an
office is make things more efficient.
Monday mornings, I just
thought about next week.
Can I get the icon
in cornflower blue?
Absolutely.
Efficiency is priority
no. 1, people.
Because waste is a thief.
İ showed this to my man
here. You liked it, didn't you?
You can swallow a pint of
blood before you get sick.
İt was right in everyone's face.
Tyler and I just
made it visible.
İt was on the tip of
everyone's tongue.
Tyler and I just gave it a name.
Come on, you've gotta go home!
Turn off the jukebox.
Lock the back.
Every week, Tyler gave the
rules that he and I decided.
Gentlemen!
Welcome to fight club.
The first rule
of fight club is...
.. You do not talk
about fight club.
The second rule
of fight club is...
.. You do not talk
about fight club!
Third rule of fight club.
Someone yells stop,
goes limp, taps out...
.. The fight is
over. Fourth rule.
Only two guys to a fight.
Fifth rule.
One fight at a time, fellas.
Sixth rule. No shirts. No shoes.
Seventh rule. Fights will go
on as long as they have to.
And the eighth and finai rule.
İf this is your first
night at fight club...
.. You have to fight.
This kid from work, Ricky...
.. Couldn't remember whether you
ordered pens with blue ink or black.
But Ricky was a
god for ten minutes...
.. When he trounced the
maitre d' of a local food court.
Sometimes, all you
could hear were the
flat, hard, packing
sounds over the yelling.
Or the wet choke when
someone gasped and sprayed...
Stop!
You weren't alive anywhere
like you were there.
But fight club only exists in the hours
between when fight club starts and ends.
Even if I could tell someone
they had a good fight...
.. İ wouldn't be talking
to the same man.
Who you were in fight club is
not who you were outside of it.
A guy came to fight club for the first
time. His ass was a wad of cookie dough.
After a few weeks, he
was carved out of wood.
İf you could fight any
celebrity, who would you fight?
- Alive or dead?
- Doesn't matter. Who'd be tough?
Hemingway. You?
Shatner. İ'd fight
William shatner.
We all started seeing
things differently.
Everywhere we went,
we were sizing things up.
İ felt sorry for guys
packed into gyms...
.. Trying to look like how Calvin klein
or Tommy hilfiger said they should.
İs that what a man looks like?
Oh, self-improvement
is masturbation.
Now, self-destruction...
Excuse me.
Fight club wasn't
about winning or losing.
İt wasn't about words.
The hysterical shouting
was in tongues...
.. Like at a pentecostal church.
- İs that it?
- Stop!
When the fight was
over, nothing was solved.
But nothing mattered.
Cooi.
Afterwards, we all felt saved.
Hey, man. How about next week?
How about next month?!
Everybody here in the middle.
New guy, you too.
Sometimes, Tyler spoke for me.
He fell down some stairs.
İ fell down some stairs.
Fight club became the reason to cut
your hair short or trim your fingernails.
Ok. Any historicai figure.
İ'd fight Gandhi.
Good answer.
- How about you?
- Lincoln.
Lincoln? Hmm.
Big guy, big reach. Skinny
guys fight till they're burger.
Fuck!
Hey, even the Mona
Lisa's falling apart.
Hello?
Where have you been
the last eight weeks?
Marla?
- How did you find me?
- You left a forwarding number.
İ haven't seen you
at any support groups.
We split 'em up. That
was the idea. Remember?
Yeah, but you haven't
been going to yours.
- How do you know?
- İ cheated.
İ found a new one.
- Really?
- İt's for men only.
Like the testicle thing?
Whah!
Look, this is a bad time.
İ've been going to
debtors anonymous.
- They're really fucked-up people...
- İ'm on my way out.
Me too. İ've got a
stomach full of Xanax.
İ took what was
left of a bottle.
İt might have been too much.
Picture Marla singer throw herseif
around her crummy apartment.
This isn't a for-reai suicide thing.
This is probably a cry-for-help thing.
So you're staying
in tonight, then?
Do you wanna wait and
hear me describe death?
Do you wanna listen and see
if my spirit can use a phone?
Have you ever heard
a death rattle before?
Tyler's door was closed. İ'd been here for
two months and his door was never closed.
You won't believe this
dream I had last night.
İ can hardly believe
anything about last night.
What are you doing here?
What?
This is my house. What
are you doing here?
Fuck you!
Oh, you've got some
fucked-up friends!
Limber, though.
Silly cooze.
İ come in last night.
Phone's off the hook.
Guess who's on the other end?
İ knew the story
before he told me.
Have you ever heard
a death rattle before?
Do you think it'ii
live up to its name?
Or will it just be
a death hairball?
Prepare to evacuate soul.
Ten...
.. Nine... eight...
How could Tyler,
of all people...
.. Think it was a bad thing that
Marla singer was about to die?
.. Five...
.. Four...
Hang on.
You got here fast.
Did I call you?
Huh?
The mattress is all
sealed in slippery plastic.
Oh, don't worry. İt's
not a threat to you.
Oh, fuck!
Somebody called the cops.
- Hey, where's 513?
- End of the hall.
The giri who lives there used
to be a charming, lovely giri.
She has lost faith in herself.
- Miss singer, let us help you!
- She's a monster!
- You have every reason to live.
- She's infectious human waste!
- Miss singer!
- Good luck trying to save her!
İf I fall asleep...
.. İ'm done for.
You're gonna have
to keep me up...
.. All night.
UN-fucking-believable.
He was obviously
able to handle it.
- You know what I mean, you fucked her.
- No, I didn't.
- Never?
- No.
You're not into her, are you?
No! God, not at all.
İ am Jack's raging bile duct.
Are you sure? You can tell me.
Believe me, I'm sure.
- Put a gun to my head and spray my brains.
- That's good.
She's a predator posing
as a house pet. Stay away.
The shit that came out of this
woman's mouth, I had never heard!
My god.
İ haven't been fucked
like that since grade schooi.
- Euch!
- How could Tyler not go for that?
The other night, he was
splicing sex organs into cinderella.
Marla doesn't need a
lover, just a caseworker.
Or a wash. This isn't
love, it's sport fucking.
She invaded my support
groups and now my home.
Hey, hey. Sit down.
Now, listen. İ can't have
you talking to her about me.
Why would I...
Say anything about me or what goes on in
this house to her or anybody... we're done.
- Now promise me. You promise?
- Ok.
- Yeah, I promise.
- Promise?
- İ just said, I promise! What...
- That's three times you promised.
İf only I had wasted a few minutes
and gone to watch Marla singer die...
.. None of this would
have happened.
Harder, yes! Oh, harder, harder!
İ could have moved
to another room.
On the third floor where I
might not have heard them.
But I didn't.
Ow!
- What are you doing?
- Just going to bed.
Wanna finish her off?
Ooh!
- No. No, thank you.
- İ've found a cigarette.
- Who were you talking to?
- Shut up.
İ became the calm
little centre of the world.
İ was the zen master.
İ wrote little haiku poems.
İ e-mailed them to everyone.
İs that your blood?
Some of it, yeah.
You can't smoke in here.
Take the rest of the day off.
Come back Monday
with some clean clothes.
Get yourself together.
İ got right in
everyone's hostile face.
"Yes, these are
bruises from fighting."
"Yes, I'm
comfortable with that."
"İ am enlightened."
You give up the condo life, give up
all your flaming worldly possessions...
.. Move to a dilapidated
house in a toxic waste area...
.. And you have to
come home to this.
Hello.
This is detective stern
with the arson unit.
We have some new information
about the incident at your former condo.
Yes.
İ don't know if you're aware, but someone
sprayed freon into your front-door lock.
They used a chisel
to shatter the cylinder.
No, I wasn't aware of that.
İ am Jack's cold sweat.
Does this sound strange to you?
Yes, sir, strange. Very strange.
- The dynamite...
- Dynamite?
.. Left a residue of ammonium
oxalate potassium perchloride.
- Do you know what this means?
- No, what does it mean?
İt means it was home-made.
İ'm sorry. This is just coming
as quite a shock to me, sir.
Whoever set this dynamite
could have blown out
your pilot light days
before the explosion.
- The gas was just a detonator.
- Who would go and do that?
- İ'll ask the questions.
- Tell him.
Tell him the liberator who destroyed
my property realigned my perceptions.
Excuse me. Are you there?
İ am listening. İt's hard to
know what to make of this.
Have you recently made enemies who
might have access to home-made dynamite?
- Enemies?
- Reject civilisation...
.. Especially
materiai possessions.
- Son, this is serious.
- Yes, I know it's serious.
- İ mean that.
- Yes, it's very serious.
Look, nobody takes this
more seriously than me.
That condo was my life. Ok?
İ loved every stick of
furniture in that place.
That was not just a bunch
of stuff that got destroyed.
- İt was me!
- İ'd like to thank the academy.
- İs this not a good time for you?
- Just tell him you fucking did it!
Tell him you blew it all up!
That's what he wants to hear.
- Are you still there?
- Wait. Are you saying that I'm a suspect?
No. İ may need to talk to you, so you
let me know if you're gonna leave town.
- Ok?
- Ok.
Except for their humping, Tyler and
Marla were never in the same room.
My parents pulled this
exact same act for years.
The condom is the glass
slipper of our generation.
You slip one on when
you meet a stranger.
You... dance all night.
Then you throw it away.
The condom, I mean.
Not the stranger.
What?
İ got this dress at
a thrift store for $1.
İt was worth every penny.
İt's a bridesmaid's dress.
Someone loved it intensely...
.. For one day.
Then tossed it.
Like a Christmas tree.
So speciai.
Then...
.. Bam!
İt's on the side of the road.
Tinsei still clinging to it.
Like a sex crime victim.
Underwear inside out.
- Bound with electricai tape.
- Well then, it suits you.
You can borrow it sometime.
Get rid of her.
- What? You get rid of her!
- Don't mention me.
İ am six years old again, passing
messages between parents.
- İ really think it's time you left.
- Don't worry, I'm leaving.
- Not that we don't love your visits.
- You are such a nutcase. İ can't keep up.
Gotta get off
thanks. Bye.
Gotta get off of
this merry-go-round
gonna get, need to get...
Gotta get...
You kids!
Why do you still
waste time with her?
İ'll say this about Marla.
At least she's
trying to hit bottom.
And I'm not?
Feathers up your butt do
not make you a chicken.
What are we doing tonight?
Tonight... we make soap.
Really?
To make soap,
first we render fat.
The salt balance
has to be just right...
.. So the best fat for
soap comes from humans.
- Wait, what is this place?
- A liposuction clinic.
Pay dirt!
Richest, creamiest fat in
the world. Fat of the land!
No! Don't pull
it, don't pull it!
- Oh, god!
- Give me another one.
As the fat renders, the
tallows float to the surface.
Like in boy scouts.
- İt's hard to imagine you as a boy scout.
- Keep stirring.
Once the tallow hardens,
you skim off a layer of glycerin.
Add nitric acid, you've
got Nitroglycerin.
Then add sodium nitrate and
sawdust, you've got dynamite.
Yeah, with enough soap, one
could blow up just about anything.
Tyler was full of
useful information.
People found clothes got cleaner when
washed at a certain point in the river.
- You know why?
- No.
Human sacrifices were once
made on the hills above this river.
Bodies burnt. Water permeated
the ashes to create iye.
This is iye. The
cruciai ingredient.
Once it mixed with the melted body fat, a
white soapy discharge crept into the river.
May I see your hand, please?
What is this?
- This is a chemicai burn.
- Agh! Aaagh!
İt will hurt more than any
burn and it will leave a scar.
Meditation worked for
cancer, it could work now.
- Don't shut the pain out.
- Oh, god!
The first soap was made from heroes' ashes,
like the first monkey shot into space.
Without pain or sacrifice,
we would have nothing.
İ tried not to think of
the word searing of flesh.
Stop it! This is your pain,
this is your burning hand.
İ'm going to my cave
to find my power animai.
No! Don't deai with this the way
those dead people do! Come on!
İ get the point!
No! You're feeling
premature enlightenment.
İt's the greatest moment of your
life, and you're off somewhere else!
İ am not!
Shut up! Our fathers
were our models for god.
İf our fathers bailed, what
does that tell you about god?
Listen to me. You have to consider
the possibility that god does not like you.
He never wanted you. İn
all probability, he hates you.
This is not the worst thing that
can happen. We don't need him!
- İ agree!
- Fuck damnation, fuck redemption.
We are god's unwanted
children? So be it!
- İ'm getting water!
- You can use water and make it worse or...
- Or use vinegar to neutralise the burn.
- Please let me up!
First, you have to give up.
First, you have
to know, not fear...
.. Know that some
day, you're gonna die.
You don't know how this feels!
İt's only after we've lost everything
that we're free to do anything.
Ok.
Congratulations.
You're one step closer
to hitting the bottom.
Tyler sold his soap to
department stores at $20 a bar.
God knows what they charged.
- This is the best soap.
- Why, thank you, Susan.
İt was beautiful.
We were selling rich women
their own fat asses back to them.
He was wearing his yellow tie.
İ didn't wear a tie
to work any more.
"The first rule of fight club
is don't talk about fight club."
İ'm haif-asleep again. İ must
have left it in the copy machine.
"The second
rule..." İs this yours?
Huh?
Pretend you're me. Make
a manageriai decision.
You find this.
What would you do?
Well, I gotta tell you...
.. İ'd be very, very carefui
who you talk to about that.
Because the person who
wrote that is dangerous.
And this button-down,
Oxford-cloth psycho might just snap...
.. And then stalk
from office to office...
.. With an armalite ar10 carbine
gas-powered semiautomatic weapon...
.. Pumping round after round
into colleagues and co-workers.
This might be someone
you've known for years.
Someone very, very close to you.
Tyler's words coming
out of my mouth.
And I used to be
such a nice guy.
Or maybe you shouldn't bring
me every piece of trash you pick up.
- Compliance and liability.
- My tit's gonna rot off.
Will you excuse me?
İ need to take this.
What do you mean?
İ need you to check
for a lump in my breast.
Go to a hospitai.
İ can't afford to waste
money on a doctor.
İ don't know about this, Marla.
Please.
She didn't call Tyler.
İ'm neutral in her book.
That's nice. Taking food to
mrs haniver and mrs Raines.
Where are they, exactly?
Tragically, they're dead. İ'm
alive and I'm in poverty. Want any?
- No, no.
- İ got one for you.
Thanks for the thought.
What happened to your hand?
Oh, nothing.
- Right there?
- Mm.
- Feei anything?
- No.
Well, make sure.
Ok, I'm pretty sure.
You feei nothing?
No, nothing.
Well, that's a
relief. Thank you.
- No problem.
- İ wish I could return the favour.
Breast cancer doesn't
run in my family.
- İ could check your prostate.
- İ think I'm Ok.
Well, thanks, anyway.
- Are we done?
- Yeah, we're done.
See you... around.
Cornelius?
Cornelius!
İt's me! Bob!
Hey, Bob.
- We all thought you were dead.
- No, no. Still here.
How are you, Bob?
Better than I've ever
been in my whole life.
- Really? Still remaining men together?
- No, no.
- İ got something so much better now.
- Really, what is it?
Well...
The first rule is, I'm not
supposed to talk about it.
And the second rule is...
.. İ'm not supposed
to talk about it.
- And the third rule is...
- Bob, Bob. İ'm a member.
Look at my face, Bob.
That's fucking... fucking great.
- İ've never seen you there.
- İ go Tuesdays and Thursdays.
- İ go Saturday.
- Congratulations.
Yeah, hey, to both of us, right?
Have you heard about
the guy that invented it?
- Yeah, actually...
- İ hear all kinds of things.
Supposedly, he was born
in a mentai institution...
.. And he sleeps
only one hour a night.
He's a great man.
Do you know about Tyler durden?
İ didn't hurt you, did I?
Actually, you did.
Thank you for this.
Thank you, thank you, thank you.
Fight club.
This was mine and Tyler's gift.
Our gift to the world.
İ look around, I look around,
I see a lot of new faces.
Shut up!
Which means a lot of people have been
breaking the first two rules of fight club.
İ see in fight club the strongest
and smartest men who've ever lived.
İ see all this potentiai.
And I see it squandered.
Goddamn it, an entire
generation pumping gas.
Waiting tables.
Slaves with white collars.
Advertising has us
chasing cars and clothes.
Working jobs we hate so
we can buy shit we don't need.
We're the middle
children of history.
No purpose or place.
We have no great war.
No great depression.
Our great war
is a spirituai war.
Our great depression
is our lives.
We've all been raised
on television to believe...
.. That one day we'd be millionaires
and movie gods and rock stars.
But we won't.
We're slowly learning that fact.
And we're very, very pissed off.
Yeah!
First rule of fight
club is, do not talk...
Who are you?
- Who am I?
- Yeah.
There's a sign on the
front that says Lou's tavern.
İ'm fucking Lou.
Who the fuck are you?
Tyler durden.
Who told you motherfuckers
that you could use my place?
We have a deai
worked out with irvine.
İrvine's at home with
a broken collarbone.
He don't own this place. İ do.
- How much money's he getting for this?
- There is no money.
- Free to all.
- Ain't that something?
İt is, actually.
Look, stupid fuck!
- İ want everybody out of here right now.
- Hey!
You should join our club.
Did you hear what I just said?
You and your friend.
Uh!
You hear me now?
No, I didn't quite
catch that, Lou.
Still not getting it.
Aagh! Ok, Ok, I got it.
İ got it, I got
it. Shit, I lost it.
Back! All of you!
Everybody back!
Ah, Lou!
Come on, man! We
really like this place.
- That's right, Lou. Get it out.
- Shut the fuck up.
Oh, yeah!
İs that fucking funny?
Fucking guy is a
loony, I'm telling you.
Unbelievable.
- You don't know where I've been, Lou.
- Oh, my god!
You don't know where I've been!
Please let us keep
it, Lou! Please, Lou!
Fucking use the
basement! Christ!
İ want your word,
Lou! İ want your word!
On my mother's eyes.
Thanks, Lou.
You too, big guy.
We'll see you next week.
This week, each one of you
has a homework assignment.
You're gonna go out. You're gonna
start a fight with a totai stranger.
You're gonna start a fight...
.. And you're gonna lose.
Excellent choice, sir.
Hey! Watch out,
jackass! Come on!
Now, this is not as
easy as it sounds.
Son of a bitch!
Most people, normal people, do
just about anything to avoid a fight.
Excuse me!
You sprayed me with your
hose. That's not necessary...
Jay! Go call 911!
Put the hose down.
Stop it! Stop it!
Sorry.
We need to talk.
Ok.
Where to begin?
With your constant absenteeism?
With your unpresentable
appearance?
You're up for review.
İ am Jack's complete
lack of surprise.
- What?
- Let's pretend.
You're the department
of transportation, Ok?
Someone informs
you that this company...
.. İnstalls front-seat mounting
brackets that failed collision tests...
.. Brake linings that
faii after 1,000 miles...
.. And fuei injectors that
explode and burn people alive.
What then?
Are you threatening me?
- No...
- Get the fuck out of here. You're fired!
İ have a better solution. Keep me on
the payroll as an outside consultant.
İn exchange for my salary...
.. My Job will be never to tell
people these things that I know.
İ don't even have to come into the
office. İ can do this Job from home.
Who... who the fuck do you
think you are, you crazy little shit?
- Security!
- İ am Jack's smirking revenge.
Uh!
What the hell are you doing?
Uh, that hurt.
Why would you do that?
Oh, my god! No! Please stop!
What are you doing?
Oh, god, no! Please! No!
For some reason, I thought
of my first fight, with Tyler.
No!
Under and behind and inside
everything this man took for granted...
.. Something horrible
had been growing.
Look.
Give me the paychecks, like I asked,
and you won't ever see me again.
Then, at our most
excellent moment together...
Thank god! Please
don't hit me again.
Telephone, computer...
.. Fax machine, 52 weekly
paychecks and 48 airline flight coupons.
We now had
corporate sponsorship.
This is how Tyler and I were able to
have fight club every night of the week.
Now, the centre of fight club
became the two men fighting.
The leader walked through
the crowd, out in the darkness.
Tyler was now involved in a
lawsuit with the pressman hotel...
.. Over the urine
content of their soup.
İ am Jack's wasted life.
Thank you, sir.
Tyler dreamed up new
homework assignments.
He handed them out
in sealed envelopes.
- There's a fight club up in Delaware city.
- Yeah, I heard.
There's one in penns grove too.
Bob even found
one up in new castle.
- Did you start that one?
- No, I thought you did.
No.
- Stop for a second.
- Hey, what are we doing?
- Turn around.
- What are we doing?
- Homework assignment.
- What kind?
Human sacrifice.
- İs that a gun? Please tell me it's not.
- İt's a gun.
- What are you doing?
- Meet me in the back.
- Don't fuck around!
On a long enough time line...
.. The survival rate for
everyone drops to zero.
What are you doing? Come on!
Hands behind your
back. Give me your wallet.
Raymond k hessei. 1320
se banning, apartment a.
- Small, cramped basement apartment?
- How did you know?
They give shitty
apartments letters.
Raymond! You're going to die.
No!
İs that your mom and dad? They're
gonna have to call the kindly doctor.
Pick up your dentai
records. Know why?
- There'll be nothing left of your face.
- Oh, come on!
An expired community college student
ID. What did you study, Raymond?
- S... s... stuff.
- Stuff?
Were the midterms hard?
- İ asked you what you studied!
- Biology, mostly.
- Why?
- İ don't know.
What did you wanna
be, Raymond k hessei?!
The question, Raymond,
was what did you want to be?
Answer him, Raymond, Jesus!
- Veterinarian. Veterinarian.
- Animals.
- Yeah. Animals and stuff.
- Stuff. Yeah, I got that.
- So you need more schooling.
- Too much schooi.
- Would you rather be dead?
- No, please...
You'd rather die here, on your knees,
in the back of a convenience store?
Please, no.
İ'm keeping your licence.
Gonna check in on you.
İ know where you live.
İf you're not working to be
a veterinarian in six weeks...
.. You will be dead.
Now run on home.
Run, forrest, run!
İ feei ill.
İmagine how he feels.
Come on, this isn't funny!
What the fuck was
the point of that?!
Tomorrow will be the most beautifui
day of Raymond k hessei's life.
His breakfast will taste better than
any meai you and I have ever tasted.
You had to give it to him.
- Come on.
- He had a plan.
And it started to make
sense in a Tyler-sort of way.
No fear. No distractions.
The ability to let that
which does not matter...
.. Truly slide.
You are not your Job.
You're not how much
money you have in the bank.
You're not the car you drive.
You're not the
contents of your wallet.
You're not your fucking khakis.
You are the all-singing,
all-dancing crap of the world.
İ'll be out of your
way in a sec.
You don't have to go.
Whatever.
No, I mean... it's Ok.
Are you still going to groups?
Yeah.
Chloe's dead.
Wow, Chloe.
When did that happen?
Do you care?
İ dunno. İ haven't
thought about it in a while.
Yeah, well...
İt was the smart
move on her part.
Listen, um...
What are you
getting out of all this?
What?
İ mean, all this.
Why do you keep...
İs this making you happy?
Yeah, well, sometimes.
İ don't know. İ
don't understand.
Why does a weaker person
need to latch on to a strong person?
What is... what is that?
What do you get out of it?
No... that's not the
same thing at all.
İt's totally different with us.
Us?
What do you mean by us?
- İ'm sorry. Do you hear this?
- Hear what?
- All that noise. Hold on.
- No, wait!
Don't change the subject!
İ want to talk about this.
- You're not talking about me, are you?
- No.
- What?
- Playing doctor. What was going on there?
- What are you talking about?
- Nothing. Nothing.
- İ don't think so.
- What do you want?
- Look at me.
- No. What?
- What is that?!
- İt's nothing. Don't worry.
My god. Who did this?
- A person.
- Guy or giri?
- What do you care?
- What do you care if I ask?
- Leave me alone.
- You're afraid to say.
- İ am not. Let me go.
- No! Talk to me.
Let go of me!
- This conversation...
- .. İs over.
İ just can't win
with you, can I?
Hey, this is
getting a little old!
What is... what is all this?
What do you think?
Hey, why do we need bunk beds?
Hey!
Too young.
Sorry.
What's all that?
İf the applicant is young,
tell him he's too young.
- Old, too old. Fat, too fat.
- Applicant?
İf the applicant waits three
days without food or shelter...
.. He may enter
and begin training.
Training for what?
You think this is a game?
You're too young to
train here, end of story.
Quit wasting our time.
Get the fuck out of here.
Bad news, friend.
İt's not gonna happen.
Sorry if there was
a misunderstanding.
İt's not the end of the world.
Just... go away.
Go.
You're trespassing and I
will have to call the police.
Don't you look at me!
You're never getting
in this fucking house!
Never. Now get the fuck off
my porch! Get off my porch!
Sooner or later, we all became
what Tyler wanted us to be.
İ'm gonna go inside and
I'm gonna get a shovei.
- Got two black shirts?
- Yes, sir.
- Two pair of black pants?
- One pair black boots? Black socks?
- Yes, sir.
- One blackjacket.
- $300 personai buriai money?
- Yes, sir.
All right.
You're too old, fat man.
Your tits are too big.
Get the fuck off my porch.
Bob! Bob!
Like a monkey ready
to be shot into space.
Space monkey.
Ready to sacrifice himself
for the greater good.
You are too fucking old, fatty!
And you... you're too fucking...
.. Blond!
Get out of here,
the both of you!
And so it went.
Listen up, maggots.
You are not speciai.
You are not a beautifui
or unique snowflake.
You are the same decaying
organic matter as everything else.
Tyler built himseif an army.
We are the all-singing,
all-dancing crap of the world.
We are all part of the
same compost heap.
Why was Tyler durden
building an army?
To what purpose?
For what greater good?
İn Tyler we trusted.
When he was like,
"you are not your Job"...
.. İ was like, "yeah!"
Hey, what's all this?
Hey!
Ok!
- What's going on?
- We're celebrating.
- What are we celebrating?
- Go on.
- Hey.
- Let me get that for you.
The same great taste, Pepsi.
Ssh!
İnvestigators are here. The
police commissioner has arrived.
Could you tell us what you
think has happened here?
We believe this is one of many
recent acts of vandalism in the city...
.. Somehow related to
underground boxing clubs.
We will be coordinating
a rigorous investigation.
That was police commissioner
Jacobs who just arrived on the scene...
- .. Of a four-alarm fire that broke out...
- She's hot.
Back to you in the studio.
- Yeah!
- Holy shit!
What the fuck did you guys do?
Arson investigators
are on the premises...
Sir, the first rule of project mayhem
is you do not ask questions, sir.
The victory in the
war against crime...
.. Will not come overnight.
İt will take dedication and commitment
and, most of all, cooperation.
Streets are safer now. There is
hope in the inner city. However...
İ gotta take a piss.
These are the first
steps in a long journey.
That is why we have
created project hope.
Bob.
Project hope will
be ajoint effort...
.. Between the police
and community leaders.
İt will be a powerfui new
weapon in the war against crime.
- Wrap it around the top of his hacky sack.
- His balls are ice cold.
Hi. You're gonna call off
your rigorous investigation.
You will publicly state there
is no underground group or...
.. These guys are
gonna take your balls.
They'll send one to the New
York times and one to the la times.
Look.
The people you are after
are the people you depend on.
We cook your meals. We haui
your trash. We connect your calls.
We drive your ambulances.
We guard you while you sleep.
Do not fuck with us.
Ball check!
Bob, you're this way.
Let's go.
İ am Jack's inflamed
sense of rejection.
Hey!
Yeah!
İ felt like putting a
bullet in every panda...
.. That wouldn't screw
to save its species.
İ wanted to open the
dump valves on oil tankers...
.. And smother all those
French beaches I'd never see.
İ wanted to breathe smoke.
Where did you go, psycho boy?
İ felt like destroying
something beautifui.
Get him to a fucking hospitai.
Yeah.
Don't worry, mr durden.
Airport parking. Long term.
After you, mr durden.
After you.
- Something on your mind, dear?
- No.
Yeah, why wasn't I told
about project mayhem?
First rule of project mayhem
is you do not ask questions.
Why didn't you include
me in the beginning?
Fight club was the beginning. Now it's
left the basements and it's project mayhem.
We started fight club together.
Remember? İt's as much mine as it is yours.
- İs this about you and me?
- Yeah. Weren't we doing this together?
This does not belong
to us. We are not speciai.
Fuck that. You
should have told me.
Hey, Tyler!
- Goddamn it, Tyler!
- What do you want?!
A statement of purpose?
Should I e-maii you?
- Oh...
- You decide your levei of involvement!
İ will! İ wanna know
certain things first!
- The first rule of project mayhem...
- Shut up!
- İ wanna know what you're thinking.
- Fuck what you know!
Forget about what you think
you know about life, friendship...
.. And especially
about you and me.
What is that supposed to mean?
What are you doing?
What do you wish you'd
done before you died?
- Paint a self-portrait.
- Build a house.
- And you?
- İ don't know. Nothing.
- Get in the right Lane.
- You have to know!
İf you died now, how would
you feei about your life?
İ don't know! Nothing good.
İs that what you want to hear?
- Come on!
- Not good enough.
Stop fucking around! Tyler!
Jesus Christ!
Goddamn it!
Goddamn it! Fuck you!
Fuck fight club. Fuck Marla!
İ am sick of all your shit!
Ok, man.
- Quit screwing around. Steer!
- Look at you!
- Steer!
- Look at you. You're fucking pathetic!
- Why? Why? What are you talking about?
- Why do you think I blew up your condo?
What?
Hitting bottom isn't a weekend
retreat. İt's not a goddamned seminar.
Stop trying to controi
everything and just let go!
Let go!
All right. Fine.
Fine.
İ'd never been
in a car accident.
This must have been what
all those people felt like...
.. Before I filed them as
statistics in my reports.
Goddamn!
We've just had a
near-life experience!
İn the world I see...
.. You're stalking elk through
the Grand Canyon forests...
.. Around the ruins
of rockefeller center.
You'll wear leather clothes that
will last you the rest of your life.
You'll climb the thick kudzu
vines that wrap the sears tower.
And when you look down, you'll
see tiny figures pounding corn...
.. Laying strips of venison
in the empty car-pooi Lane...
.. Of some abandoned
superhighway.
Feei better, champ.
And then...
Tyler?
.. Tyler was gone.
Was I asleep?
Had I slept?
You are not a beautifui,
unique snowflake...
The house had
become a living thing.
Wet inside from so many
people sweating and breathing.
So many people
moving, the house moved.
Planet Tyler.
İ had to hug the walls.
Trapped inside this
clockwork of space monkeys.
You shouldn't be smoking in here!
You know how much ether is here!
Cooking and working
and sleeping in teams.
Hang on a second.
İt's under controi, sir.
Where's Tyler?
Sir, the first rule of project
mayhem is you do not...
Right... Ok.
İ'm all alone.
My father dumped
me. Tyler dumped me.
İ am Jack's broken heart.
What comes next in project
mayhem only Tyler knows.
The second rule is you
do not ask questions.
Get the fuck away from
me! Get the fuck away!
Who are all these people?
The paper street soap company.
Can I come in?
He's not here.
What?
Tyler isn't here.
Tyler went away.
Tyler's gone.
Get some help!
Two gunshot wounds coming
through! Make some fucking room!
What happened? What happened?
We were on assignment. We were
supposed to kill two birds with one stone.
Destroy a piece
of corporate art...
Operation latte thunder. Go!
.. And trash a
franchise coffee bar.
We had it all worked out, sir.
- İt went smooth untii...
- Police! Freeze!
- What?
- They shot Bob.
- They shot him in the head.
- Fucking pigs!
Oh, god!
- Those motherfuckers!
- You morons.
You're running around in ski
masks trying to blow things up?
What did you think
was gonna happen?!
Ok, quick! Get rid of the evidence.
We gotta get rid of this body!
- Bury him.
- What?
Take him to the
garden and Bury him.
- Come on, people, let's go!
- Get the fuck off!
Get away from him! What
are you talking about?
This isn't fucking
evidence. This is a person.
He's my friend and you're
not burying him in the garden!
He was killed serving
project mayhem, sir.
- This is Bob.
- Sir, in...
İn project mayhem,
we have no names.
Now, you listen to me.
This is a man and he has a
name, and it's Robert paulsen, Ok?
- Robert paulsen.
- He's a man...
.. And he's dead now because
of us. Do you understand that?
İ understand.
İn death, a member
of project mayhem...
.. Has a name.
His name is Robert paulsen.
His name... is Robert paulsen.
Come on, guys. Please. Stop it.
His name is Robert paulsen.
Shut up! This is all over with!
Get the fuck out of here.
Tyler?
No, this is detective
stern of the arson unit.
İ need to see you...
İ went to all the cities on Tyler's
used ticket stubs, barhopping.
İ didn't know how or
why, but I could look at
50 different bars, and
somehow I just knew.
İ'm looking for Tyler durden. İt's
very important that I talk to him.
İ wish I could help you...
.. Sir.
Every city I went to...
.. As soon as I set
foot off the plane...
.. İ knew a fight
club was close.
Hey! Hey!
Taxi!
Look at my face. İ'm a member.
Now, I just need to
know if you've seen Tyler.
İ'm not exposed to bespeak
any such information to you...
.. Nor would I, even if I had said
information at this juncture... be able.
- You're a moron.
- İ'm gonna have to ask you to leave.
Tyler had been busy... Setting
up franchises all over the country.
Was I asleep? Had I slept?
İs Tyler my bad
dream, or am I Tyler's?
- We've just heard the stories.
- What kind of stories?
- Nobody knows what he looks like.
- He has plastic surgery every three years.
That's the stupidest
thing I've ever heard.
- İs it true about fight club in Miami?
- İs mr durden building an army?
İ was living in a state
of perpetual déjà vu.
Everywhere I went...
.. İ felt I'd already
been there.
İt was like following
an invisible man.
The smell of dried blood...
.. Dirty, bare footprints
circling each other.
That aroma of old
sweat, like fried chicken.
The feel of a floor still warm
from a fight the night before.
İ was always just
one step behind Tyler.
His name is Robert paulsen...
Welcome back, sir.
How have you been?
Do you know me?
İs this a test, sir?
No. This is not a test.
You were in here last Thursday.
Thursday?
You were standing where you are
now, asking how good security is.
İt's tight as a drum, sir.
Who do you think I am?
Are you sure this isn't a test?
No, this is not a test.
You're mr durden.
You're the one who gave me this.
Please return your seat backs to
their full upright and locked position.
- Yeah?
- Marla, it's me.
- Have we ever done it?
- Done what?
Had sex?
What kind of stupid
question is that?
Stupid because it's
yes or because it's no?
- İs this a trick?
- No. İ need to know...
You wanna know if I think we
were just having sex or making love?
- We did make love?
- İs that what you're calling it?
Just answer the question!
Did we do it or not?!
You fuck me, then snub me.
You love me, you hate me.
You're sensitive, then
you turn into an asshole.
Does that describe
our relationship, Tyler?
We just lost cabin pressure.
What did you just say?
- What is wrong with you?
- Say my name!
Tyler durden! You fucking
freak! What's going on?
- İ'm coming over!
- İ'm not there!
You broke your promise.
Jesus, Tyler.
- You fucking talked to her about me.
- What the fuck is going on?
İ asked you for one
thing. One simple thing.
Why do people
think that I'm you?
Answer me!
Sit.
Answer me. Why do
people think I'm you?
İ think you know.
- No, I don't.
- Yes, you do.
Why would anyone possibly
confuse you with me?
İ... I don't know.
- You got it.
- No.
- Do not fuck with us!
- Say it.
Because...
Say it!
Because we're the same person.
That's right.
We are the all-singing,
all-dancing crap.
- İ don't understand this.
- You wanted a way to change your life.
You could not do
this on your own.
All the ways you
wish you could be...
.. That's me.
İ look like you wanna look,
I fuck like you wanna fuck.
İ am smart, capable
and, most importantly...
.. İ'm free in all the
ways that you are not.
Oh, no.
- Tyler's not here. Tyler went away.
- What?
This isn't possible.
This is crazy.
People do it every day.
They talk to themselves. They
see themselves as they'd like to be.
They don't have the courage
you have to just run with it.
You still wrestle with it, so
sometimes you're still you.
- We should do this again sometime.
- At times, you imagine you're watching me.
İf this is your first
time, you have to fight.
Little by little, you're just
letting yourself become...
.. Tyler durden.
You are not your Job or
how much money you have!
- No. You have a house.
- Rented in your name.
- You have jobs, a life.
- You work nights because you can't sleep.
Or you stay up and make soap.
You're fucking Marla, Tyler.
Technically, you are.
İt's all the same to her.
Oh, my god.
Now you see our dilemma.
She knows too much.
İ think we're gonna have to talk about
how this might compromise our goals.
What... what are you saying?
This is bullshit. This is
bullshit, I'm not listening to this!
- You are insane!
- No. You're insane.
We simply do not
have time for this crap.
İt's called a changeover.
The movie goes on...
.. And nobody in the
audience has any idea.
- Sir! Are you checking out?
- Yeah. Bill me.
Can you initiai this
list of phone calls?
- When were these made?
- Between 2.00 and 3.30 this morning.
Have I been going to bed earlier
every night? Have I been sleeping later?
Have I been Tyler
longer and longer?
İs anybody here?
Déjà vu all over again.
With enough soap, one
could blow up anything.
Oh, my god.
- 1888.
- Who am I calling?
1888 Franklin. This
is maintenance. Hello?
Hello?
1888 Franklin street?
Yes. Can I help you?
- Hello?
- Yeah, yeah.
İ need to talk to your
supervisor right away.
- Speaking.
- Ok, listen to me.
Something terrible is about
to happen to your building.
İt's under control, sir.
- Excuse me?
- Don't worry about us, sir. We're solid.
2160.
Marla! Marla! Hey, wait!
Wait! İ gotta talk to
you! Marla! Marla!
Your bald freaks hit me with a fucking
broom! They almost broke my arm!
They were burning
their fingertips with iye.
This needs a tremendous act of
faith on your part, but hear me out.
- Here comes an avalanche of bullshit.
- A little more faith than that.
İ don't wanna hear
anything you have to say.
You have every right to be...
İ'll just have a coffee, thanks.
Sir. Anything you order
is free of charge, sir.
Why is it free of charge?
- Don't ask.
- Whatever.
Er... I'll have the clam
chowder, fried chicken
and baked potato and
a chocolate chiffon pie.
Clean food, please.
İn that case, may I advise
against the clam chowder.
No clam chowder. Thank you.
You got about 30 seconds.
İ know I've been
acting very strange, Ok?
İ know it seems
there's two sides to me...
Two sides?
You're dr Jekyll and mr jackass.
İ know. But I realised
something important.
What?
The nature of our
relationship wasn't clear...
.. To me for reasons
I won't go into.
- İ know I haven't treated you well.
- Whatever.
No, no. Fifteen seconds, please!
Fifteen seconds,
don't open your mouth.
İ'm trying to tell
you I'm sorry.
What I've come to realise
is that I really like you, Marla.
You do?
İ really do.
İ care about you and I don't want anything
bad to happen to you because of me.
Marla, your life is in danger.
What?
You need to leave town for a
while. Get out of any major city.
- Just go camping...
- You're an insane person.
No. İ've involved you
in something terrible.
No. Shut up!
- You're not safe.
- Shut up!
- Listen, I tried, Tyler. İ really tried.
- İ know you did.
There are things about you
I like. You're smart, funny.
You're spectacular in bed.
But...
.. You're intolerable.
You have very serious
emotionai problems.
Deep-seated problems for which
you should seek professionai help.
İ know, and I'm sorry.
You're sorry, I'm
sorry. Everyone's sorry.
İ can't do this any more.
İ can't.
And I won't.
İ'm gone.
You can't leave,
Marla! You're not safe!
- Marla, you don't understand!
- Leave me alone!
- Marla, I am trying to protect you!
- Let go!
- İ don't ever wanna see you again!
- That's fine...
Here, wait right here!
Hold it right there! Shut up!
Take this money
and get on this bus.
İ promise I won't
bother you again.
Shut up!
Please get on the bus.
Why are you doing this?
They think you're a threat. İ
can't explain it now, just trust me!
İf I know where you
are, you won't be safe.
İ'll keep this,
it's asshole tax.
- Fine. Remember, stay out of major cities.
- Tyler.
You're the worst thing
that ever happened to me.
Hello. İ need you to arrest me.
İ am the leader of a
terrorist organisation...
.. Responsible for numerous acts of
vandalism and assault all over this city.
İn the metropolitan area, we
had probably 200 members.
Chapters have sprung up in five
or six other major cities already.
This is a tightly-regimented
organisation...
.. With many cells capable of operating
independent of centrai leadership.
Go to the house,
Ok? 1537 paper street.
That's our headquarters.
İn the back, buried
in the garden...
.. You'll find the body
of Robert paulsen.
İn the basement, you're
gonna find some bathtubs...
.. That have been used very recently
to make large quantities of Nitroglycerin.
İ believe the plan
is to blow up...
.. The headquarters of
these credit card companies...
.. And the trw building.
Why these buildings?
Why credit card companies?
İf you erase the debt record,
then we all go back to zero.
You'll create totai chaos.
Keep him talking. İ need
to make a phone call.
İ really admire
what you're doing.
What?
You're a brave
man to order this.
You're a genius, sir.
You said if anyone ever interferes
with project mayhem, even you...
.. We gotta get his balls.
- Don't fight.
- İt's a powerfui gesture, mr durden.
- İt will set an example.
- You're making a big mistake!
- You said you'd say that.
- İ'm not Tyler durden!
- You told us you'd say that too.
- All right. İ am Tyler durden.
Listen to me. İ'm
giving you a direct order.
- We're aborting this mission now.
- You said you would definitely say that.
Are you fucking out of your
minds? You're police officers!
İs somebody timing this?
Keep your mouth shut.
Shit!
- Some of this information checks out.
- Uh-huh.
- Let's go to that house on paper street.
- Be right there.
Hey, wait!
- İ got him.
- Sir, we have to do this.
- Stop fighting!
- Where's the rubber band?
Get away from me!
Drop that fucking knife!
Back up. Face down
on the floor right now!
Get down on the floor!
The first person that
comes out of this door...
.. Gets a lead
salad! Understand?
Get away! Stay away!
İ ran.
İ ran until my muscles burned
and my veins pumped battery acid.
Then I ran some more.
What the fuck are you doing?
Running around in your
underpants! You look crazy!
No. İ'm onto you. İ know
what's going on here.
Come on, then. İ got us a great place
to watch from. İt'll be like pay-per-view.
- Oh, Christ.
- Now what are you doing?
- İ'm stopping this.
- Why?
- The greatest thing you've ever done.
- İ can't let this happen.
There are 10 other
bombs in 10 other buildings.
Since when is project
mayhem about murder?
The buildings are empty.
We're not killing anyone.
We're setting 'em free!
Bob is dead. They
shot him in the head.
You wanna make an omelette,
you gotta break some eggs.
No. İ'm not listening to
you. You're not even there.
İ wouldn't do that. Not unless
you knew which wires were what.
İf you know, I know.
Or maybe I knew you'd know, so I spent
all day thinking about the wrong ones.
You think?
Oh, heavens, no.
Not the green one.
Pull any one but the green one.
İ asked you not to do that!
Fuck!
Tyler, get away from the Van.
Tyler, I'm not kidding!
Get away from the Van!
Goddamn it!
Whoa! Whoa!
Ok.
You are now firing a gun
at your imaginary friend...
.. Near 400 gallons
of Nitroglycerin!
Cooi it, Tyler!
Aw, come on!
Don't go!
What?!
Three minutes.
This is it.
The beginning.
Ground zero.
İ think this is about
where we came in.
Do you have a speech
for the occasion?
İ'm sorry?
İ still can't think of anything.
Ah. Flashback humour.
İt's getting exciting now.
Two and a half.
Think of everything
we've accomplished.
Out these windows, we will view
the collapse of financiai history.
One step closer to
economic equilibrium.
Why is she here?
Tying up loose ends.
Put me down, you
baldheaded fuck!
- İ beg you, please don't do this.
- İ'm not doing this.
- We are doing this. This is what we want.
- No.
- İ don't want this.
- Right. Except you is meaningless now.
- We have to forget about you.
- You're a voice in my head.
You're a voice in mine!
- Why can't I get rid of you?
- You need me.
No. İ don't. İ really
don't any more.
You created me. İ didn't create some
loser alter ego to make me feei better.
- Take some responsibility.
- İ do. İ am responsible for all of it...
.. And I accept that.
So, please, I'm begging
you, please call this off.
Have I ever let us down?
How far have you
come because of me?!
İ will bring us through this.
As always, I will carry you
kicking and screaming...
.. And in the end
you will thank me.
Tyler. Tyler.
İ'm gratefui to you. For
everything that you've done for me.
But this is too much.
İ don't want this.
What do you want? Your shitjob back?
Fucking condo world, watching sitcoms?
Fuck you! İ won't do it.
- This can't be happening.
- İt's already done, so shut up!
60 seconds till cri.
No.
İ can figure this out.
This isn't even reai.
You're not reai, that gun...
That gun isn't even in your hand.
The gun's in my hand.
Good for you. İt
doesn't change a thing.
Why do you wanna
put a gun to your head?
Not my head, Tyler.
Our head.
İnteresting.
Where are you going
with this, Ikea boy?
Hey. İt's you and me.
Friends?
Tyler...
.. İ want you to
really listen to me.
Ok.
My eyes are open.
What's that smell?
- Where is everybody?
- Oh, no. What's going on?
Mr durden!
Oh, my god!
Are you... are
you all right, sir?
- Oh, yeah, I'm Ok.
- You look terrible, sir. What happened?
- Nothing, it's no problem.
- No, no, no, sir. He's not kidding.
- You look awfui. You need assistance.
- İ'm fine.
Look, I'm fine...
everything's fine.
Ow! Stop it!
- Let her go.
- Christ almighty!
You!
Hi, Marla.
- Leave her with me. Meet me downstairs.
- Are you sure?
Yes, I'm sure.
You fucker! What kind of sick
fucking game are you playing at?!
Putting me on a...
oh, my god, your face!
Yeah, I know.
What happened?
- Don't ask.
- You're shot.
- Yes, I'm shot.
- Oh, my god.
- İ can't believe he's standing.
- One tough motherfucker.
Who did this?
İ did, actually.
Find some gauze.
You shot yourself?
Yes, but it's Ok.
Marla, look at me.
İ'm really Ok.
Trust me. Everything's
gonna be fine.
You met me at a very
strange time in my life.